<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Updates from Robert</title>
  <id>http://localhost/recent.atom</id>
  <updated>2014-01-14T15:30:05Z</updated>
  <link href="http://localhost/" />
  <link href="http://localhost/recent.atom" rel="self" />
  <generator>Werkzeug</generator>
  <entry xml:base="http://localhost/recent.atom">
    <title type="text">Polishing the Strategy</title>
    <id>http://localhost/polishing-the-strategy</id>
    <updated>2014-01-14T15:30:05Z</updated>
    <published>2014-01-14T15:30:05Z</published>
    <link href="http://localhost/polishing-the-strategy" />
    <author>
      <name>damien72</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bob.thusoy.com/robot-badass-strategy.html&quot;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; we saw our basic strategy, which hasn't changed a lot throughout the project. Until recently!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few days, we tried to optimize the code and changed some aspects in Robert's behaviour:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now start with full magazine (one ball already on the arm), start our patrol and immediately throw this ball when we reach the net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some balls are placed close to the net and thanks to our routine having been optimized, those balls are caught and thrown quickly afterwards. 
This is a pretty huge improvement because the robot used to finish his turn (~19s) before throwing this ball over the net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan to optimize also the turning detection, which you will get more information about in a new article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, our program runs thanks to three main tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;collect&lt;/em&gt;, which uses the color sensor and keeps making the arm rotate until we catch a red or a blue ball (which sets the flag ballLoaded).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;trace&lt;/em&gt;, which prevents our robot from running into the net in case we have performed a bad turn. If it's the case, the robot stops and changes direction to go away from the net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt;, which in essence starts with a setup of the unmetioned sensors and applies the strategy we've talked about, making calls to collect and trace at the right time.
We also use a Bluetooth connection with the NXT in order to get directly information about the robot on a computer. We already showed the code for the server &lt;a href=&quot;http://bob.thusoy.com/anal-expulsiveness.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; abd also added two files for our robot, btio and btlog, that waits for a connection and enables the robot to send messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://localhost/recent.atom">
    <title type="text">Robot Badass Strategy</title>
    <id>http://localhost/robot-badass-strategy</id>
    <updated>2014-01-13T15:05:35Z</updated>
    <published>2014-01-13T15:05:35Z</published>
    <link href="http://localhost/robot-badass-strategy" />
    <author>
      <name>Damien Roeder</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;As you may have seen on some photographs of our robot, we have &lt;strong&gt;one big rotating arm (G)&lt;/strong&gt; in the middle and two smaller ones on each front side in order to grab the balls.
Apart from the tracks(E+F), we add on top of that &lt;strong&gt;a bunch of sensors&lt;/strong&gt; whose roles are to help the robot navigate on the field:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Robert fully equipped for battle&quot; src=&quot;/static/img/architecture.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a &lt;em&gt;color sensor (D)&lt;/em&gt;, to detect when we have caught a blue or red ball. In that case we want the robot to stop moving the arm, finish his turn and go to the net in order to throw the ball over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a &lt;em&gt;touch sensor (A)&lt;/em&gt;, to detect when we hit a wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;an &lt;em&gt;ultrasonic sensor (C)&lt;/em&gt;, to detect the net since we are not supposed to touch it (as it is the case for the walls) unless we want to lose points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a &lt;em&gt;light sensor (B)&lt;/em&gt;, to be sure we follow correctly the net without running into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with that arsenal, we need an effective and not too complex &lt;strong&gt;strategy&lt;/strong&gt;. Here is what we agreed on:
The robot starts on his landing area and performs some patrols around the field. When a ball is caught, we finish our round in order to face the net, stop and &lt;del&gt;FIRE!&lt;/del&gt; throw the ball over. And whatnot...
However, problems may occur when we haven't found any ball for a while. In that case, we change the radius of effect and perform smaller or wider squares to be sure we take a bite out of something!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is funny and interesting about our strategy is that unlike many other groups, we are basically not looking for any ball. We merely rely on the fact that the patrol leads to having some balls caught by the rotating arm, which eventually makes our coding easier.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://localhost/recent.atom">
    <title type="text">Here comes the Hotstepper</title>
    <id>http://localhost/here-comes-the-hotstepper</id>
    <updated>2013-12-13T12:15:44Z</updated>
    <published>2013-12-13T12:15:44Z</published>
    <link href="http://localhost/here-comes-the-hotstepper" />
    <author>
      <name>Tarjei Husøy</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This almost resembles intelligence. Scary stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/81998207&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://localhost/recent.atom">
    <title type="text">Anal expulsiveness</title>
    <id>http://localhost/anal-expulsiveness</id>
    <updated>2013-12-13T11:49:53Z</updated>
    <published>2013-12-13T11:49:53Z</published>
    <link href="http://localhost/anal-expulsiveness" />
    <author>
      <name>Tarjei Husøy</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Our lil' friend went through a quite rebellious stage the last days, but we now seem to have outgrown the worst problems - the toddler has started talking! After a lengthy search through available libraries for communicating with NXT devices over bluetooth, we've finally settled on &lt;code&gt;jaraco.nxt&lt;/code&gt;, as it's the only one we got working within a reasonable time-frame, has the correct abstraction level and happens to be written in python. And as a bonus, available through PyPI, which makes it all so much more pleasant to get started. Documentation is not great, but the source code is succinct enough to be easily read, and it ships with a couple of working examples to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we want the bluetooth communication anyway? Purely for debugging purposes. Lil' Bobby is expected to navigate around the playing field on his own, being aware of his own approximate coordinates on the field so that he can avoid colliding with the net, and to be able to throw stuff over the net when that time comes. Implementing this logic would not be too hard in a pure software emulation, but implementing this on a hardware device in, you know, &lt;em&gt;real life&lt;/em&gt;, comes the brutality of working with cheap sensors and inaccurate motors. So we use the bluetooth connection purely for debugging, writing out sensor data and debug statements so that we can monitor it during execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logging code we use for monitoring looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/thusoy/7796033.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's far from perfect though, the NXT will still lose all bluetooth communication quite haphazardly, and can only recover through a reboot. But we now have more uptime than not, a great improvement from the four hours we spent getting to this point, where connections were dropping randomly and the NXT device seemed to respond as predictably to messages as cornstarch do to the latest Kanye single. With this rolling, we managed to teach Bob collision detection and subsequent recovery, and get a rough metric of distance to nearest wall. Videos might or might not follow shortly.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://localhost/recent.atom">
    <title type="text">What I want for Christmas</title>
    <id>http://localhost/what-i-want-for-christmas</id>
    <updated>2013-12-02T21:52:07Z</updated>
    <published>2013-12-02T21:52:07Z</published>
    <link href="http://localhost/what-i-want-for-christmas" />
    <author>
      <name>Kjell Braden</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;As you saw in previous posts, Little Bobby has already materialized. All excited about his first Christmas season, he sent out the following email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;From: Robert Paulson &amp;lt;bobby13@[redacted]&amp;gt;
To: Santa Claus &amp;lt;claus@[redacted]&amp;gt;
Subject: Wishlist
Date: Sun, 01 Dec 2013 09:55:06 +0100

Dear Santa,

this is Bobby Paulson. I never had christmas before. I'm two weeks old
and have never been naughty.

What I want for Christmas:
- to be able to run around on my own
- to not run into volleyball nets
- to be able to collect and throw balls
- snow

Please note that this list is non-exhaustive.

Looking forward to hearing from you soon.
Sincerely,
Robert Paulson
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://localhost/recent.atom">
    <title type="text">By any other name</title>
    <id>http://localhost/by-any-other-name</id>
    <updated>2013-12-02T20:22:21Z</updated>
    <published>2013-12-02T20:22:21Z</published>
    <link href="http://localhost/by-any-other-name" />
    <author>
      <name>Tarjei Husøy</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I can hear you asking (and feel my team members despair), how can you name a robot Robert?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C'mon, seriously? Robert is an &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; name for a robot! But besides the awesomeness, there's actually a story behind it as well. No, I didn't say it was a good one, but I've got your attention anyway, so you'll read it whether you like it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually can't take credit for the name, my chinese roommate &lt;strong&gt;Wuyang&lt;/strong&gt; was the unvoluntary creator. We were discussing potential names for the creature when a freudian slip made the pronounciation of &quot;robot&quot; turn into something that closely resembled &quot;Robert&quot;. And it kinda stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boom, ta-da, &lt;strong&gt;done&lt;/strong&gt;! That's how hard it is. Total energy spent in the process probably in the order of a M&amp;amp;M, and it took us ~45s and a laugh. And it's still far more awesome than &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/1011/&quot;&gt;Renesmee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://localhost/recent.atom">
    <title type="text">His name is Robert Paulson</title>
    <id>http://localhost/his-name-is-robert-paulson</id>
    <updated>2013-11-26T21:40:26Z</updated>
    <published>2013-11-26T21:40:26Z</published>
    <link href="http://localhost/his-name-is-robert-paulson" />
    <author>
      <name>Tarjei Husøy</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;We reached what might not be our first, but definitively our most important milestone today; our mean, lean killing machine got his name! I'm pleased to introduce you to &lt;strong&gt;Robert&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Robert in early test stage&quot; src=&quot;/static/img/robert1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GCi_PIz5ekU&quot;&gt;brother in name&lt;/a&gt;, Bob might very well die in the end (or even before that), but in doing so he inspires a revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apocalypse might be closer than you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
